Jonathon Rigert

Web Developer, Architect, Director

jonrigert.com

jonrigert@gmail.com (630) 439-4995

Michigan, 48154

LinkedIn

About

A web developer, architect and leader with a diverse range of skills and interests. Offers over a decade of experience in building extensive web applications, committed to code quality, scalability, and best practices. Brings strong leadership qualities and a passion for mentorship, excels in highly collaborative environments.

Skills

Languages and Frameworks: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, NextJS, React Native / React Native Web

UI and Styling: Tailwind, CSS, SASS, Web Accessibility, Storybook, Styled Components / CSS-in-JS

Tools: git, jest, vitest, React Testing Library, TurboRepo, CI/CD Pipelines and Actions, Redux / Redux Saga

Backend: NodeJS, GraphQL / Apollo, SQL and noSQL Databases, Firebase / Firestore **Integrations:** React Query, Apollo Client, Axios, RTK Query, Headless CMS platforms

Experience

Bounteous, Inc. - Director, Web Application Development

July 2015 - Present

- Serves as the primary point of oversight and escalation for numerous projects
- Leads initiatives to establish practice-wide coding standards and best practices
- Aids in diagnosing and resolving complex issues
- Helped establish and facilitate a React Apprenticeship program, acting as leader and mentor
- Assists in the pitching, estimating, and technical planning of potential and established projects
- Founded and directs the Bounteous Web Development Craft, a collaborative initiative dedicated to knowledge exchange, formulating best practices, and building a supportive community
- Contributes to the planning, architecture, and development of numerous projects from inception to completion
- Leads multiple teams of developers, responsible for the technical success of various projects
- Collaborates with a diverse array of clients to plan and execute projects, recognized as a trusted partner
- Works with a multitude of technologies, with a strong focus on React
- Spearheads the development and architecture of several internal company projects

Previous Positions at Bounteous:

Associate Principal Front-End Architect (July 2021 - November 2021)

Lead Front-End Developer (August 2020 - July 2021)

Senior Front-End Application Developer (July 2015 - August 2020)

UnitedHealth Group / Optum - Senior Web Developer

April 2014 - July 2015

- Developed a large-scale digital health application in AngularJS, providing services to healthcare consumers and providers
- Senior member of the Core/Foundational team that constructed the application framework utilized by various development teams
- Part of most feature planning, architectural design and development
- Integral to the development of the "Toolkit", a JavaScript/AngularJS library that allows sharing of critical components across multiple web applications
- Member of the support team that troubleshoots environmental issues and supports major releases of the application
- Contributed to the development of an internal web application designed to streamline weekly status reporting for developers

Command Transportation — **Software Developer**

October 2012 - March 2014

- Member of the team responsible for developing an internal software system utilized by the sales and dispatch team, which tracks and aligns customer loads with carrier trucks
- Implemented new features and maintained existing platforms in WPF, C# and VB.NET
- Primarily responsible for most user interface development, collaborating closely with the design team to bring their concepts to life
- Part of the support team that diagnoses and resolves bugs reported by users
- Dedicated time to engage with users directly, observing their interactions with the software to gather valuable feedback and insights

Applied Systems, Inc. - Software Developer

March 2010 - September 2012

- Tasked with maintaining and updating insurance agency automation software in VB6 and VB.NET
- Developed new features for existing applications, updated existing functionalities, remediated defects, and rebuilt out-of-date assemblies and applications using more modern technologies
- Responsible for multiple conversions from 16-bit C++ to VB.NET to ensure compatibility with 64-bit operating systems and modern computer standards

Education

DeVry University — Bachelor of Science, Game and Simulation Programming

2005 - 2009 - Addison, IL